[Music]
hi everyone this is Ravi welcome to Tri
and tich tasar Advanced
Training as you all know I've already
published 49 YouTube videos covering
beginners intermediate and advanced
level
Concepts so from last couple of videos
onwards have started publishing realtime
scenarios where you might encounter
different types of obstacles while
automating your test cases and how can
we solve those obstacles by using
trienes task I've already published
seven realtime scenarios where we solved
seven different types of obstacles and
this is our lesson nine in terms of
real time scenarios and this is our
lesson 50 in terms of overall trien tasa
training please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos please don't forget to like
and share the video thank
you in this lesson I'm going to teach
you a realtime scenario
where you need to drag and drop an image
from one position to and another
position so how can we solve this kind
of obstacle while automating your test
cases by using tricentis tosa so let us
see first what is the obstacle that we
are going to solve for so this is our
obstacle tosa bot can fly this which is
categorized as medium let's go for
it drag the image from
left to the right to complete this
obstacle we need to Simply click on this
bot and drag and drop onto this
box that means your obstacle is done so
this is simple medium complexity so so
I'm going to explain very quickly so for
that let us go to trient
tasa so these are these are our
obstacles that we are creating from past
couple of videos right we so we have
already completed seven obstacles in our
previous lessons I would recommend you
guys to visit my previous videos so now
let us scan the objects from the
application for that right click on
obstacles folder click on scan and
select the
application so this is my application
select the application and click on scan
so now if you see here this is our bot
and this is our
Target area where we need to drop the
bot so now let us simply capture the
objects select select on screen and
click on this bot this is my tasa bot
and now let us select this box as well
which is two box okay and unselect
select on screen so now if you just
expand the filter here okay what we did
here so this is my Tas right which I
have selected now I can see this has
been uniquely identified because it is
not highlighting in orange color and
this is my object where I need to drop
the bot okay so now let me me rename
this
module with the obstacle
name select this copy this
obstacle and paste it
here and then let's save the
objects now close the window so if you
go back to
trasa so you can see this is my new
module that I have captured so now let
us automate the test case for that let's
come to left side which is blue color
module which is test case now select
obstacle double click on this and right
click on this folder and click on create
test case paste the obstacle name which
we copied
earlier so double click on this now let
us track this module whatever we
captured and drop onto your test
case let's expand this so this is your
Bot right what we need to do we need to
drag this bot for that we need to use a
function or a method called trag a
method called drag if you type drag C
you can have
drag close curly BRAC
and your action mode should be
input and I'm dragging here and I need
to
drop on this element for that I'm going
Simply use the method called drop so
this is my drop close curly
braces okay and this should be your
input action mode should be input so now
let us run this particular test case and
see what happens right click and click
on
run it is
dragging and dropping onto the new
location so you solve this automation
problem so is it is very simple two
methods for the repositioning drag and
drop right so those are the two methods
you need to remember as part of this
obstacle so if you have any queries
leave your queries in the comment box
I'll try to respond to your queries
thank
you hope you all understand the
obstacle to solve interacting with an
image
and drag and drop the image to the new
location by using drag and drag and drop
methods please do subscribe to the
channel click on Bell icon you'll
receive notifications whenever I publish
more videos thank you
[Music]